

José Pedro Pinto jpedropinto.com geral@jpedropinto.com github.com/62random (+351) 915 410 003

Location Braga, Portugal

José Pedro Pinto

Software Engineering Student, Data Scientist

About Me I'm a 22 year old software engineering graduate student who loves technology and to learn about computers and science in general. I enjoy playing music and practicing sports. I consider myself a curious, hard working, and proactive person. In my free time, I play in one of my university's music groups (Tuna Universitária do Minho), and sometimes code for fun, to try and explore new technologies.

I am currently in the fourth year of my degree and have a GPA of 16 (out of 20), while also working as a data scientist at Anybrain, a company based in Braga, Portugal. The main areas I am focusing on my master's degree are Artificial Intelligence and Performance Engineering.

Software Development Skills

Programming

JavaCPythonSQLHaskellShell

Technologies

- LinuxGitH2O
- LaTeX
 Pentaho
 Tensorflow

Experience

My earliest serious work experiences came from projects and course assignments at University of Minho.

After graduating, in the summer before enrolling my masters degree, I had the chance to participate in a business intelligence project in the context of a summer internship which was my first, yet very valuable, experience in a truly professional environment.

Since March of 2020, I have been working as a data scientist and machine learning engineer in a company that delivers solutions to the gaming industry through non-invasive analytics on biometric data. That experience has been very rewarding, not only in a professional way but also in the sense that it complements and encourages my academic journey which is tightly related to this area.

Activities and Accomplishments

2020 - Present, Data Scientist, part-time, Anybrain

Developing machine learning solutions for the gaming industry, such as continuous identification and fraud detection, using biometric data from the user's interaction with the platform.

2019, Internship in Business Intelligence, XpandIT

Took part in a project with the purpose of creating a dashboard providing insight into the execution of ETL processes in projects using the company's internal framework for Pentaho Data Integration.

2018 - 2020, *Volunteer at CeSIUM*, Centro de Estudantes de Engenharia Informática

Co-director of the Image Department of CeSIUM, a group of students which aims to enrich the activity and cooperation background amongst the software engineering students at University of Minho.



José Pedro Pinto jpedropinto.com geral@jpedropinto.com github.com/62random (+351) 915 410 003

Location Braga, Portugal

2017 - Present, Discourse Instance System Administrator

System administrator of a small forum running Discourse and deployed using Docker and DigitalOcean, with about 300 users.

2017, LI1 Hall of Fame, Universidade do Minho

Awarded to the best projects in the Informatics Laboratories 1 course.

2016, *Honor Student, High School*, E. Secundária Carlos Amarante Awarded to the top students in the 12th grade.

Interests

Professional

Artificial intelligence, high performance computing, internet of things and automation.

Personal

Classical and folk music (especially stringed instruments), cinema and reading.

Education

2013 - 2016, Escola Secundária Carlos Amarante

Sciences and Technologies - *Curso Cientifico-Humanístico de Ciências e Tec*nologias

2016 - 2021, Universidade do Minho

Integrated Master's Degree in Software Engineering - *Mestrado Integrado* em Engenharia Informática

Communication Skills

I'm very confortable with speaking in public, to large audiences as well as for more private contexts such as project presentations. I'm also very confortable with speaking and writing in english.